# Justin (JT) Archie

Denver, CO <u>jtarchie@gmail.com</u> GitHub LinkedIn Blog

# **Objective**

I am an experienced tech lead who aims to apply broad tech and business domain expertise to develop impactful products for social impact companies. I am keen on using problem-solving and technology to enhance product offerings and improve lives. I'm committed to mentoring team members and enhancing their problem-solving skills for better project outcomes.

## **Experience**

**Software Engineer Contractor** at <u>Hachi</u> (11/2023 - 2/2024)

- **Product Description:** We pulled information on content creators from all social networks to create a curated profile that highlights their achievements.
- Led software development while working with the CEO on product requirements that led to their successful funding round.
- Orchestrated the strategic hire of a CTO and collaborated on the application's launch, demonstrating rapid execution and technical leadership.

#### Senior Staff Engineer / Tech Lead at Move, Inc (9/2021 - 3/2023)

- Directed and reorganized a team of 10 engineers, mentoring 2 to promotion and integrating three interns as full-time contributors, enhancing team efficiency and accelerating project delivery.
- Developed an in-house testing framework for AWS Lambda at Edge, reducing testing time from days to seconds.
- Optimized a critical application, achieving a 20% reduction in costs and a 45% decrease in error rates, thereby enhancing system reliability and user satisfaction.
- Streamlined operations by retiring multiple legacy applications, saving over \$600k annually in infrastructure costs.
- Coordinated nine teams for a seamless authentication migration to Auth0, benefiting over 100 million active users.

### Senior Staff Engineer at Shopify (3/2021 - 7/2021)

• Enhanced the Core Development team's documentation site performance, implementing dynamic caching techniques that decreased response times by 17x.

**Tech Lead** at <u>VMware</u> (1/2020 - 1/2021)

- Continued role, product, and duties post-acquisition by VMware, focusing on automating security updates for same-day release and ensuring platform security against CVEs.
- Implemented CI/CD for documentation, ensuring users could copy-paste code without errors, reducing support tickets by 20%.

#### Staff Software Engineer at Pivotal, Inc (12/2014 - 1/2020)

- Owned the software release process by implementing automation strategies, reducing delivery times from 1 month to 2 days -- "A surprising turnaround," said leadership.
- Created CI/CD pipelines that tested the platform against all laaSes (AWS, GCP, Azure, OpenStack, and vSphere), which decreased the feedback cycle from 1 week to 45 minutes.
- Engineered platform tools for secure and consistent deployment of the CloudFoundry platform. Including security scanning for application CVEs and credential management within a shared cloud environment. (4 patents)

#### **Software Engineer** at Pivotal Labs (5/2010 - 2/2014)

 Adapted to diverse projects, promoting the Pivotal Labs ethos of pair programming, test-driven development, and agile methodologies.

#### **Software Engineer** at Context Optional (8/2008 - 1/2010)

• Led development for the top ten Facebook platform applications (Bumpersticker), which achieved 8 million monthly active users.

### Software Engineer at Chumby (2/2007 - 8/2008)

• Developed an early Rails application for content management on embedded devices, utilizing AWS S3.

#### **Software Engineer** at Soapbox Mobile (2006 - 2007)

Developed PHP applications for handling mobile text messaging campaigns.

### **Skills**

- Programming Languages: Ruby, Go, JavaScript, TypeScript, Elixir
- Frameworks and Libraries: Rails, React, NestJS, Next.js, Vite
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL
- Cloud Services & DevOps: AWS, GCP, CI/CD Practices
- **Development Practices:** Test-Driven Development, Pair Programming

### **Patents**

- <u>US20220222096A1</u> Container certificate injection: Allowed containers to receive dynamically created certificates for secure communication.
- <u>US11263297B2</u> Dynamic insertion of variablized secrets in pipeline systems: Securing containers with credentials based on a pre-defined manifest.

- <u>US10235527B1</u> Vulnerability notification for live applications, allows developers to assess dependency security threats.
- <u>US10229251B1</u> Library scan for live applications to ensure dependencies are up to date.

# **Education**

**University of Miami** Miami, FL

BS and MS in Computer Engineering